Telecommunications International Union Records 5758
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Telecommunications International Union Records
1934-1986
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
International Telecommunication Union
5758
75 cubic feet
76 linear ft.
Manuscripts, articles, reports, pamphlets, correspondence.
3338468
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183> kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, April 29, 1999
EAD encoding:
Randall Miles, April 18, 2014
Biographical / Historical
The majority of the members and officers of the Telecommunications International Union were women. At one time the union represented more than l00,000 telephone workers in the U.S. and Canada. At a special convention held in February l986 delegates voted to dissolve the TIU. Vice- President Joan Noonan remarked "we have earned a very distinguished place in the history of the labor movement... and we can hold our heads high and be proud."
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: 5758 OH: Telecommunications International Union Oral History Interviews
International Telecommunication Union
3338468
- Constitutions (Alliance of Independent Telephone Unions-Upstate telephone Employees Association) and Executive Committee Files (1971-1973). (Box 1)
  - Alliance of Independent Telephone Unions, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Telecommunications International Union, 1975-1985 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Telecommunications International Union, 1975-1985 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Telecommunications International Union, 1975-1985 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Telecommunications International Union, 1975-1985 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Telecommunications International Union, 1975-1985 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Telecommunications International Union, 1975-1985 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Telecommunications International Union, 1975-1985 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Telecommunications International Union, 1975-1985 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Telecommunications International Union, 1975-1985 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Telecommunications International Union, 1975-1985 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Telecommunications International Union, 1975-1985 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Telecommunications International Union (Box 1, Folder 12a)
  - Commercial Telephone Workers (CTW) Local 663, 1961-1982 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Communications Union Canada (CUC), 1973 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Connecticut Union of Telephone Workers (CUTW), 1971-1984 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Diamond State Telephone Commercial Union (DSTCU), 1971-1983 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Federation of Telephone Workers of Pennsylvania (FTWP), 1970-1976 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Federation of Women Telephone Workers (FWTW), 1969 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - International Brotherhood of Telephone Workers (IBTW), 1961-1965 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Indiana Bell Commercial Employees Association (ICGA), 1967 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - New England Federation of Telephone Traffic Workers (NEFTTW), 1967 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Point Breeze Salaried Employees' Association Inc. (PBSEA), 1972-1984 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Pennsylvania Telephone Guild (PTG), 1966-1982 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Telephone Commercial Employees Union (TCEU), 1977-1982 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Telephone Commercial Union (TCU), 1960-1982 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Telephone Employees Organization (TEO), 1960-1982 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Telecommunications International Union California Local, 1979-1982 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Telephone Traffic Union (New York), 1949-1982 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Telephone Traffic Union (Upstate New York), 1949-1985 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Union of Telephone Workers, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - United Telephone Workers of Delaware, 1963-1977 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Upstate Telephone Employees Association, 1975-1982 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Miscellaneous Constitutions and related documents (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Executive Committee Files, 1971-1973 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Executive Committee Files, 1971-1973 (Box 1, Folder 35)
- Executive Committee Files (1974-1980). (Box 2)
  - Executive Committee Files, 1974-1975 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Executive Committee Files, 1975-1977 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Executive Committee Files, 1975-1977 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Executive Committee Files, 1975-1977 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Executive Committee Files, 1975-1977 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Executive Committee Files, 1975-1977 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Executive Committee Files, 1975-1977 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Executive Committee Files, 1975-1977 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Executive Committee Files, 1975-1977 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Executive Committee Files, 1975-1977 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Executive Committee Files, 1975-1977 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Executive Committee Files, 1975-1977 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Executive Committee Files, 1975-1977 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Executive Committee Files, 1975-1977 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Executive Committee Files, 1975-1977 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Executive Committee Files, 1975-1977 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Executive Committee Files, 1978-1980 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Executive Committee Files, 1978-1980 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Executive Committee Files, 1978-1980 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Executive Committee Files, 1978-1980 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Executive Committee Files, 1978-1980 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Executive Committee Files, 1978-1980 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Executive Committee Files, 1978-1980 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Executive Committee Files, 1978-1980 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Executive Committee Files, 1978-1980 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Executive Committee Files, 1978-1980 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Executive Committee Files, 1978-1980 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Executive Committee Files, 1978-1980 (Box 2, Folder 28)
- Executive Committee Files (1981-1986). (Box 3)
  - Executive Committee Files, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Executive Committee Files, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Executive Committee Files, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Executive Committee Files, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Executive Committee Files, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Executive Committee Files, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Executive Committee Files, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Executive Committee Files, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Executive Committee Files, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Executive Committee Files, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Executive Committee Files, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Executive Committee Files, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Executive Committee Files, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Executive Committee Files, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Executive Committee Files, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Executive Committee Files, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Executive Committee Files, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Executive Committee Files, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Executive Committee Files, 1983 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Executive Committee Files, 1983 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Executive Committee Files, 1983 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Executive Committee Files, 1983 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Executive Committee Files, 1983 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Executive Committee Files, 1983 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Executive Committee Files, 1983 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Executive Committee Files, 1983 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Executive Committee Files, 1983 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Executive Committee Files, 1984 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Executive Committee Files, 1984 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Executive Committee Files, 1984 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Executive Committee Files, 1984 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Executive Committee Files, 1984 (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Executive Committee Files, 1984 (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - Executive Committee Files, 1984 (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - Executive Committee Files, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - Executive Committee Files, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - Executive Committee Files, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - Executive Committee Files, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 38)
  - Executive Committee Files, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 39)
  - Executive Committee Files, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 40)
  - Executive Committee Files, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 41)
  - Executive Committee Files, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 42)
  - Executive Committee Files, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 43)
  - Executive Committee Files, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 44)
  - Executive Committee Files, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 45)
  - Executive Committee Files, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 46)
  - Executive Committee Files, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 47)
  - Executive Committee Files, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 48)
  - Executive Committee Files, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 49)
  - Executive Committee Files, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 50)
  - Executive Committee Files, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 51)
  - Executive Committee Files (Box 3, Folder 52)
- Officers Files (1962-1975). (Box 4)
  - John W. Shaughnessy, Jr., President, Correspondence, 1962 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    Scope and Contents
    (Shaughnessy as President of Connecticut Union of Telephone Workers) Correspondence with Larry Gauley, General Secretary, United Telephone Organization, re. organizing.
  - John W. Shaughnessy, Jr., President, Correspondence, 1963 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    (Shaughnessy as President of Alliance of Independent Telephone Unions) re. NLRB election.
  - John W. Shaughnessy, Jr., President, Correspondence, 1964 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    Routine.
  - John W. Shaughnessy, Jr., President, Correspondence, 1965 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    re. withdrawal of Point Breeze Salaried Employees' Association, Inc. from Alliance of Independent Telephone Unions; negotiation of issues for 1966; other routine.
  - John W. Shaughnessy, Jr., President, Correspondence, 1966 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    re. withdrawal of Federation of Telephone Workers from Alliance of Independent Telephone Unions; plans for legislative conference; Teamsters and Communications Workers raiding; other routine.
  - John W. Shaughnessy, Jr., President, Correspondence, 1967 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    re. bargaining policy; legislative efforts; meeting arrangements; other routine.
  - John W. Shaughnessy, Jr., President, Correspondence, 1968 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    re. meeting arrangements for conferences; other routine.
  - John W. Shaughnessy, Jr., President, Correspondence, 1969 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    Miscellaneous company financial data.
  - John W. Shaughnessy, Jr., President, Correspondence, 1970 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - John W. Shaughnessy, Jr., President, Correspondence, 1971 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - John W. Shaughnessy, Jr., President, Correspondence, 1971 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - John W. Shaughnessy, Jr., President, Correspondence, 1971 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - John W. Shaughnessy, Jr., President, Correspondence, 1971 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - John W. Shaughnessy, Jr., President, Correspondence, 1971 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - John W. Shaughnessy, Jr., President, Correspondence, 1971 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - John W. Shaughnessy, Jr., President, Correspondence, 1971 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - John W. Shaughnessy, Jr., President, Correspondence, 1971 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - John W. Shaughnessy, Jr., President, Correspondence, 1971 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - John W. Shaughnessy, Jr., President, Correspondence, 1971 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - John W. Shaughnessy, Jr., President, Correspondence, 1971 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - John W. Shaughnessy, Jr., President, Correspondence, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - John W. Shaughnessy, Jr., President, Correspondence, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - John W. Shaughnessy, Jr., President, Correspondence, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - John W. Shaughnessy, Jr., President, Correspondence, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - John W. Shaughnessy, Jr., President, Correspondence, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - John W. Shaughnessy, Jr., President, Correspondence, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - John W. Shaughnessy, Jr., President, Correspondence, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - John W. Shaughnessy, Jr., President, Correspondence, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - John W. Shaughnessy, Jr., President, Correspondence, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - John W. Shaughnessy, Jr., President, Correspondence, 1973 (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - John W. Shaughnessy, Jr., President, Correspondence, 1973 (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - John W. Shaughnessy, Jr., President, Correspondence, 1973 (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - John W. Shaughnessy, Jr., President, Correspondence, 1973 (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - John W. Shaughnessy, Jr., President, Correspondence, 1973 (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - John W. Shaughnessy, Jr., President, Correspondence, 1973 (Box 4, Folder 35)
  - John W. Shaughnessy, Jr., President, Correspondence, 1973 (Box 4, Folder 36)
  - John W. Shaughnessy, Jr., President, Correspondence, 1973 (Box 4, Folder 37)
  - John W. Shaughnessy, Jr., President, Correspondence, 1973 (Box 4, Folder 38)
  - John W. Shaughnessy, Jr., President, Correspondence, 1973 (Box 4, Folder 39)
  - John W. Shaughnessy, Jr., President, Correspondence, 1973 (Box 4, Folder 40)
  - John W. Shaughnessy, Jr., President, Correspondence, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 41)
    re. raiding, beginning of national bargaining; CWA President Joseph Beirne urging Alliance of Independent Telephone Unions to merge with them; routine letter from President Gerald Ford, August 23, 1974.
  - John W. Shaughnessy, Jr., President, Correspondence, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 42)
  - John W. Shaughnessy, Jr., President, Correspondence, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 43)
  - John W. Shaughnessy, Jr., President, Correspondence, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 44)
  - John W. Shaughnessy, Jr., President, Correspondence, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 45)
  - John W. Shaughnessy, Jr., President, Correspondence, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 46)
  - John W. Shaughnessy, Jr., President, Correspondence, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 47)
  - John W. Shaughnessy, Jr., President, Correspondence, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 48)
  - John W. Shaughnessy, Jr., President, Correspondence, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 49)
  - John W. Shaughnessy, Jr., President, Correspondence, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 50)
  - John W. Shaughnessy, Jr., President, Correspondence, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 51)
  - John W. Shaughnessy, Jr., President, Correspondence, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 52)
  - John W. Shaughnessy, Jr., President, Correspondence, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 53)
    Routine, January to June.
  - John W. Shaughnessy, Jr., President, Correspondence, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 54)
  - John W. Shaughnessy, Jr., President, Correspondence, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 55)
  - John W. Shaughnessy, Jr., President, Correspondence, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 56)
  - John W. Shaughnessy, Jr., President, Correspondence, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 57)
  - John W. Shaughnessy, Jr., President, Correspondence, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 58)
- Officers Files (1975-1980). (Box 5)
  - John W. Shaughnessy, Jr., President, Correspondence, 1975 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    July-December, re. reorganization and change of name from Alliance of Independent Telephone Unions to Telecommunications International Union (ff.4).
  - John W. Shaughnessy, Jr., President, Correspondence, 1975 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - John W. Shaughnessy, Jr., President, Correspondence, 1975 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - John W. Shaughnessy, Jr., President, Correspondence, 1975 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - John W. Shaughnessy, Jr., President, Correspondence, 1975 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - John W. Shaughnessy, Jr., President, Correspondence, 1975 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - John W. Shaughnessy, Jr., President, Correspondence, 1976 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    Routine letter from Vice President-elect Walter F. Mondale, November 13, 1976 (ff.17).
  - John W. Shaughnessy, Jr., President, Correspondence, 1976 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - John W. Shaughnessy, Jr., President, Correspondence, 1976 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - John W. Shaughnessy, Jr., President, Correspondence, 1976 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - John W. Shaughnessy, Jr., President, Correspondence, 1976 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - John W. Shaughnessy, Jr., President, Correspondence, 1976 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - John W. Shaughnessy, Jr., President, Correspondence, 1976 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - John W. Shaughnessy, Jr., President, Correspondence, 1976 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - John W. Shaughnessy, Jr., President, Correspondence, 1976 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - John W. Shaughnessy, Jr., President, Correspondence, 1976 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - John W. Shaughnessy, Jr., President, Correspondence, 1976 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - John W. Shaughnessy, Jr., President, Correspondence, 1976 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - John W. Shaughnessy, Jr., President, Correspondence, 1977 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - John W. Shaughnessy, Jr., President, Correspondence, 1977 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - John W. Shaughnessy, Jr., President, Correspondence, 1977 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - John W. Shaughnessy, Jr., President, Correspondence, 1977 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - John W. Shaughnessy, Jr., President, Correspondence, 1977 (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - John W. Shaughnessy, Jr., President, Correspondence, 1977 (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - John W. Shaughnessy, Jr., President, Correspondence, 1977 (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - John W. Shaughnessy, Jr., President, Correspondence, 1977 (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - John W. Shaughnessy, Jr., President, Correspondence, 1977 (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - John W. Shaughnessy, Jr., President, Correspondence, 1977 (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - John W. Shaughnessy, Jr., President, Correspondence, 1977 (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - John W. Shaughnessy, Jr., President, Correspondence, 1977 (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - John W. Shaughnessy, Jr., President, Correspondence, 1978 (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - John W. Shaughnessy, Jr., President, Correspondence, 1978 (Box 5, Folder 32)
  - John W. Shaughnessy, Jr., President, Correspondence, 1978 (Box 5, Folder 33)
  - John W. Shaughnessy, Jr., President, Correspondence, 1978 (Box 5, Folder 34)
  - John W. Shaughnessy, Jr., President, Correspondence, 1978 (Box 5, Folder 35)
  - John W. Shaughnessy, Jr., President, Correspondence, 1978 (Box 5, Folder 36)
  - John W. Shaughnessy, Jr., President, Correspondence, 1978 (Box 5, Folder 37)
  - John W. Shaughnessy, Jr., President, Correspondence, 1978 (Box 5, Folder 38)
  - John W. Shaughnessy, Jr., President, Correspondence, 1978 (Box 5, Folder 39)
  - John W. Shaughnessy, Jr., President, Correspondence, 1978 (Box 5, Folder 40)
  - John W. Shaughnessy, Jr., President, Correspondence, 1978 (Box 5, Folder 41)
  - John W. Shaughnessy, Jr., President, Correspondence, 1978 (Box 5, Folder 42)
  - John W. Shaughnessy, Jr., President, Correspondence, 1979 (Box 5, Folder 43)
    re. possible affiliation with AFL-CIO (ff.45); other routine.
  - John W. Shaughnessy, Jr., President, Correspondence, 1979 (Box 5, Folder 44)
  - John W. Shaughnessy, Jr., President, Correspondence, 1979 (Box 5, Folder 45)
  - John W. Shaughnessy, Jr., President, Correspondence, 1979 (Box 5, Folder 46)
  - John W. Shaughnessy, Jr., President, Correspondence, 1979 (Box 5, Folder 47)
  - John W. Shaughnessy, Jr., President, Correspondence, 1979 (Box 5, Folder 48)
  - John W. Shaughnessy, Jr., President, Correspondence, 1979 (Box 5, Folder 49)
  - John W. Shaughnessy, Jr., President, Correspondence, 1979 (Box 5, Folder 50)
  - John W. Shaughnessy, Jr., President, Correspondence, 1979 (Box 5, Folder 51)
  - John W. Shaughnessy, Jr., President, Correspondence, 1979 (Box 5, Folder 52)
  - John W. Shaughnessy, Jr., President, Correspondence, 1979 (Box 5, Folder 53)
  - John W. Shaughnessy, Jr., President, Correspondence, 1979 (Box 5, Folder 54)
  - John W. Shaughnessy, Jr., President, Correspondence, 1980 (Box 5, Folder 55)
    January-February, Information on Occupational Job Evaluation; other routine.
  - John W. Shaughnessy, Jr., President, Correspondence, 1980 (Box 5, Folder 56)
- Officers Files (1980-1982). (Box 6)
  - John W. Shaughnessy, Jr., President, Correspondence, 1980 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    March-December, 5-page memo to "Futuristics Committee" from Shaughnessy re. direction of TIU (ff.1); 4-page memo and national bargaining agenda sent to TIU members re. negotiations with American Telephone and Telegraph Company; issues of "TIU Bargaining News" (ff.4-); re. Quality of Work Life Committee and minutes of first meeting (ff.10); other routine.
  - John W. Shaughnessy, Jr., President, Correspondence, 1980 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - John W. Shaughnessy, Jr., President, Correspondence, 1980 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - John W. Shaughnessy, Jr., President, Correspondence, 1980 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - John W. Shaughnessy, Jr., President, Correspondence, 1980 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - John W. Shaughnessy, Jr., President, Correspondence, 1980 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - John W. Shaughnessy, Jr., President, Correspondence, 1980 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - John W. Shaughnessy, Jr., President, Correspondence, 1980 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - John W. Shaughnessy, Jr., President, Correspondence, 1980 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - John W. Shaughnessy, Jr., President, Correspondence, 1980 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - John W. Shaughnessy, Jr., President, Correspondence, 1981 (Box 6, Folder 11)
    Correspondence re. affiliation with United Telegraph Workers, AFL-CIO (ff.17); Federation of Telephone Workers of Pennsylvania withdrawal from TIU (ff.18-19); assignment of local union numbers (ff.20-21); TIU requests affiliation with AFL-CIO (ff.21); other routine.
  - John W. Shaughnessy, Jr., President, Correspondence, 1981 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - John W. Shaughnessy, Jr., President, Correspondence, 1981 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - John W. Shaughnessy, Jr., President, Correspondence, 1981 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - John W. Shaughnessy, Jr., President, Correspondence, 1981 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - John W. Shaughnessy, Jr., President, Correspondence, 1981 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - John W. Shaughnessy, Jr., President, Correspondence, 1981 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - John W. Shaughnessy, Jr., President, Correspondence, 1981 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - John W. Shaughnessy, Jr., President, Correspondence, 1981 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - John W. Shaughnessy, Jr., President, Correspondence, 1981 (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - John W. Shaughnessy, Jr., President, Correspondence, 1981 (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - John W. Shaughnessy, Jr., President, Correspondence, 1981 (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - John W. Shaughnessy, Jr., President, Correspondence, 1982 (Box 6, Folder 23)
    re. efforts to defeat Federation of Telephone Workers of Pennsylvania; raiding Pennsylvania Telephone Guild (ff.25); exploring possibility of merging with International Federation of Professional and Technical Engineers (ff.29); AT&T restructuring (ff.29, ff.34); other routine.
  - John W. Shaughnessy, Jr., President, Correspondence, 1982 (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - John W. Shaughnessy, Jr., President, Correspondence, 1982 (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - John W. Shaughnessy, Jr., President, Correspondence, 1982 (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - John W. Shaughnessy, Jr., President, Correspondence, 1982 (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - John W. Shaughnessy, Jr., President, Correspondence, 1982 (Box 6, Folder 28)
  - John W. Shaughnessy, Jr., President, Correspondence, 1982 (Box 6, Folder 29)
  - John W. Shaughnessy, Jr., President, Correspondence, 1982 (Box 6, Folder 30)
  - John W. Shaughnessy, Jr., President, Correspondence, 1982 (Box 6, Folder 31)
  - John W. Shaughnessy, Jr., President, Correspondence, 1982 (Box 6, Folder 32)
  - John W. Shaughnessy, Jr., President, Correspondence, 1982 (Box 6, Folder 33)
  - John W. Shaughnessy, Jr., President, Correspondence, 1982 (Box 6, Folder 34)
- Officers Files (1983-1985). (Box 7)
  - John W. Shaughnessy, Jr., President, Correspondence, 1983 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    re. 1983 National Bargaining Sessions (ff.8); nationwide strike; letter from Governor (Massachusetts) Michael Dukakis urging negotiators back to bargaining table (ff.8); "State of the Union," by Shaughnessy, 13 pages (ff.9); re. divestiture of AT&T; possible affiliation with AFSCME (ff.12); testimonial dinner honoring Shaughnessy (October) by Connecticut Union of Telephone Workers.
  - John W. Shaughnessy, Jr., President, Correspondence, 1983 (Box 7, Folder 2)